https://www.vpr.org/privacy

Privacy
Privacy Policy for Vermont Public Radio This privacy statement is intended to be transparent about what is shared when using VPR.org and our digital products. As you use VPR.org and VPR’s digital services, you are using a variety of web services and platforms. Some of those services allow you to share information directly with VPR, such as your email, your donation or a comment on a story. Some services collect anonymous information passively as you use the site, such as the type of browser or operating system you are using. We Collect Some Information DirectlyOn certain occasions when you interact with VPR’d digital platforms – e.g., by joining as a member, signing up for a newsletter, or commenting on a story – you may submit information of your own accord, or be asked to do so to participate in certain activities. The services we use to collect this information include: Blackbaud - allows donation to VPR Contact Form - allows sending a message to staff MailChimp - allows VPR to send email newsletters, membership information and station updates Disqus - allows commenting on VPR stories Hearken - allows question submission for Brave Little State Typeform - allows you to update your interests and preferences and provide feedback to VPR via online surveys Other - occasional polls, surveys or forms to submit information to VPR We Collect Some Information AutomaticallyWhen you use VPR’s digital products we use cookies and other tagging or tracking technologies that interact with your browser to automatically recognize information like your IP address, what type of device you’re using, high-level location information (e.g., city or state), and your user behavior (such as how long you stay on the website and which links you click on). The services we use to collect this information include: Google Analytics - provides VPR with website usage metrics Chartbeat - provides VPR with website metrics Doubleclick For Publishers - serves underwriter and promotion messages on the site NPR Analytics - provides VPR and NPR with website usage metrics StreamGuys - provides live stream usage metrics Third-Party ServicesThe VPR.org platform is comprised of several third-party services. As you visit VPR.org or listen online, you may be using these services: NPR: Much of the VPR website is served from a shared public radio web platform, denoted by the subdomain “www” i.e. www.VPR.org Clearbearing: Most of VPR’s online archive is hosted on our own web server managed by Clearbearing, denoted by the subdomain “vprarchive” i.e. archive.VPR.org Amazon: A number of VPR’s web applications are served from the S3 hosting service, and are denoted by “apps” in the subdomain, i.e. apps.vpr.org StreamGuys: Live streams of VPR (News, Classical, BBC, Replay, or the Vermont Statehouse) are provided by StreamGuys servers. Public Media Apps - our mobile applications for iOS and Android are developed by Public Media Apps. Those apps share device data and usage stats with Google Analytics. CookiesOur services use cookies to differentiate one anonymous user from another. Without them, first-time visitors would be indistinguishable from returning users, your preferred stream would have to be chosen every time and other preferences would be lost between visits. You are more than welcome to disable cookies in your browser, with the understanding that your experience may not be as seamless as before. ChildrenVPR does not solicit or collect information (name, mailing address, email address) of children under 13. If we become aware of information collected from someone under 13, we will remove it within a reasonable time. Children between the ages of 13 and 18 must have parental permission to use our services. Parents: if you think your child has provided us with information without your consent, please see below for how to contact us, and we will remove their data within a reasonable time. Sharing Your Information With Other OrganizationsVermont Public Radio has a long established policy to never sell, rent, exchange or otherwise share donor, member or listener information with any other organization. VPR will always safeguard the information you share with us and it will remain confidential. Sharing Your Information With VendorsAs noted above, VPR engages with some outside companies to help us develop, operate, and improve the VPR Platform. Our third party vendors receive personal information only as reasonably necessary to complete services for VPR, and are contractually bound to maintain confidentiality of information and prohibited from using or disclosing personal information without permission from VPR. Sharing Your Information As Required By LawIn response to a subpoena, court order, or legal process, VPR will share only what is reasonable and necessary to comply with the legal request. European ResidentsYour privacy rights are different if you reside in the European Union. If you would like a copy of your personal data, to update your data, lodge a complaint or to rescind your permissions, please contact us. Changes to Privacy PolicyVPR may update and change these policies occasionally. Any changes to policy will be reflected on this page. Your continued use of the VPR.org platform is considered consent to these policies. Contact UsFor concerns or other questions, please contact us. Noah Villamarin-CutterDigital ServicesVermont Public Radio Change LogDate                                Description8/11/2020                     Updated domain, app developer and contact name.5/29/2018                     Much more detailed policy language added.4/11/2013                      Original policy
© 2020 Vermont Public Radio
Contact
Privacy Policy
VPR EEO Reports And Statement
Public Files: WVTI
WOXM
WVBA
WVNK
For assistance accessing our public files, please contact publicfile@vpr.net or call 802-655-9451
